-She totally winked at me!
-She did not wink at you.
여자가 나한테 윙크했다니까
- 눈이 삐었다
- 어련하시겠어
You always think somebody's
winking at you.
The One With the Princess Leia Fantasy
I say "Tupelo Honey"
by Van Morrison.
밴 모리슨의
'투펠로 허니'가 최고야
'더 웨이 위 워'가 더 낭만적이야
No way!
The most romantic song ever
was "The Way We Were."
엘튼 존 노래 중에
더 죽이는 게 있어
I think the one that Elton John wrote
for that guy on Who's the Boss?
What song was that?
무슨 노랜데?
Hold me close
Young Tony Danza
'으스러지게 꼭 안아주세요'
잘 잤니, 모니카?
-Hi, Monica.
-Hi, Mon.
- 잘 잤니?
- 안녕
Oh, my God!
- 세상에! 쟤 밤 샌 거니?
- 당연하지
Has she slept at all?
It's been three nights in a row.
3일째 저러고 있어
She finally stopped crying yesterday.
어제부터 울지는 않더니
But then she found one of Richard's
cigar butts on the terrace....
리차드가 버린 담배꽁초를
보더니 다시 시작이야
Okay, that explains it.
I got a call at 2 in the morning...
이제 알았다!
새벽에 전화를 받았는데
뭔가 찍찍거려서
쥐인 줄 알았거든
...and all I could hear
was this squeaky sound.
So I thought,
"It's a mouse or a possum."
Then I realized, like, okay...
생각해보니까, 쥐가 무슨
돈으로 전화를 걸겠니?
...where would a mouse or a possum
get the money to make the phone call?
-Morning.
- 좋은 아침!
- 안녕
네가 만들었어?
You made pancakes?
응, 맨날 하는 놈만 하지
Yeah, like there's any way
I could ever do that.
모니카네 시럽이 맛있대요
우리 자기와 맛난 아침을 먹네
Monica and Rachel had syrup
Now I can get my man to cheer up
Good morning, Joey.
- 잘 잤어, 조이?
- 좋은 아침
Good morning.
Why don't you stay home from work
and just hang out with me?
좋은 생각이 났어
오늘 하루 쉬면서
나랑 있는 거 어때?
그러고 싶지만, 자기도 일이 있고
나도 변호사 만나러 가야돼
Oh, I wish.
You have that report to finish,
and I've got to see my lawyer.
내가 이혼녀랑 사귀다니...
나도 다 컸어
I can't believe I date
a girl who's getting divorced.
I'm such a grownup.
I gotta go, I gotta go.
나 이만 갈게
키스해줘야 가지
Not without a kiss.
Maybe I won't kiss you
so you'll stay.
키스 안 해주면
안 가겠네?
Kiss her. Kiss her!
제발 해라, 해
I'll see you later, sweetie.
Bye, Joey.
있다 봐, 자기
- 잘 있어, 조이
- 잘 가, 제니스
Bye-bye, Janice.
언제 차버릴 거야?
When are you dumping her?
그럴 생각 없어
Nope.
Not this time.
Come on, quit yanking me.
너 자신을 속이지마
내가 나한테 사기를 쳐?
I'm not yanking you.
-This is Janice.
-Yeah, I know.
제니스 얘기야
나도 알아
난 행복해 죽겠다
She makes me happy.
그래, 알았어
You look me in the eye and tell me,
without blinking...
내 눈을 보고, 눈 깜짝 말고
헤어지지 않겠다고 말해봐
...that you're not breaking up
with her. No blinking.
깜빡이지마
I'm not breaking up with her!
난 헤어지지 않아
내가 발견한 걸 봐
God, look what I found in the drain!
뭔데?
What?
It's some of Richard's hair!
리차드의 머리카락이야!
이걸 어떻게 하지?
What do I do with this?
Getting it away from me
would be job one.
우선 좀 치워줄래?
It's weird, but I don't want
to throw this away.
이상해도 이해해 줘
이건 버릴 수 없어
This is all I have left of him.
그이의 마지막 흔적이야
Gross...
...drain hair.
더럽긴 더럽다
하수구에서 나온 거야
Cool! It looks like a tiny
little person drowning in your cereal.
귀여운 꼬마들이 수영한다고
생각하면 괜찮을 거야
-What is wrong with me?
-You need to get some sleep.
나 미쳤나봐
- 넌 잠이 필요해
- 난 리차드가 필요해
I need to get some Richard.
You broke up with him for a reason.
- 이미 널 떠난 사람이야
- 그래, 알아
I know. I know.
I'm just so tired of missing him.
그리워하기도 괴롭고
전화 기다리기도 지겨워
Tired of wondering why he
hasn't called. Why hasn't he?
왜 전화를 안 할까?
Maybe because you told him not to?
네가 하지 말랬잖아
What are you, the Memory Woman?
그런 건 좀 잊어줄래?
They're not breaking up!
Chandler and Janice?
안 헤어진대!
챈들러가 제니스랑 안 헤어진대
눈 깜짝도 안 해
They're not breaking up!
He didn't blink!
그게 뭐 대수야?
두 사람 정말 잘 어울리잖아
I'm not surprised.
Have you seen them together?
They're really cute.
잘 어울려? 제니스랑?
제니스 기억나?
"Cute"? This is Janice!
You remember Janice?
Yes, I remember. She's annoying.
But you know what?
기억해, 좀 짜증나는
스타일이지만
우리 친구가 선택한 여자인데
뭘 어쩌겠어?
She's his girlfriend now.
I mean, what can we do?
그거야! 그게 우정이지
우리가 어째야 할까?
There you go! That's the spirit
I'm looking for! "What can we do?"
누구 말 좀 해봐, 로스?
All right, who's first, huh? Ross?
챈들러는 제니스만 보면
행복하다니까 그냥 받아들이자
Chandler's our friend,
and Janice makes him happy.
So I say we be adult about it
and accept her.
We'll call that Plan B.
그런 걸 차선책이라고 하지
Honey...
- 궁금한 게 있는데...
- 뭐?
... I was wondering...
...do you still have
that Navy uniform?
지금도 해군 제복 갖고 있어?
No, I had to return it
to the costume place.
아니,
빌려온 거라 돌려줬어
고등학교 때 입던
고적대 옷은 있어
I think I have an old band uniform
from high school.
- 학창시절엔 참 순수하지
- 응
You remember not having sex
in high school, right?
Well, honey, what about you?
- 자기는 어땠어?
- 뭐가?
Do you have any fun, you know,
fantasy-type things?
내 말은... 성에 대한
환상 같은 거 없었어?
없었어
정말 하나도 없었어?
Come on. You gotta have one.
Nope.
없었어
You know what?
- 그럼 이렇게 해
- 뭐?
If you tell me, I might do it.
자기가 말해주면,
나도 말할게
좋아
스타워즈 '제다이의 귀환'
본 적 있지?
Did you ever see Return of the Jedi?
응
Do you remember the scene...
그 장면 기억해?...
...with Jabba the Hutt?
'자바' 나올 때
Well, Jabba had as his prisoner...
자바가 레아 공주를 잡았는데...
... Princess Leia.
Princess Leia was wearing...
그때 레아 공주가 금색 비키니
같은 걸 입었는데...
...this gold bikini thing.
It was pretty cool.
정말 죽였지
레아 공주와 금색 비키니?
우리 또래 남자들은 다 좋아해
Princess Leia and the gold bikini?
Every guy our age loved that.
Really?
정말?
그래, 끝내주지
It's huge! That's the moment when
she stopped being a princess...
그 장면은 공주에서 진정한
여자가 되는 순간이잖아
...and she became, like, you know,
a woman.
공주 옷 입어봤니?
Did you ever do the Leia thing?
그럼
Really? That great, huh?
그래? 그게 그렇게 좋았니?
No, it's just that I got this new
pager, and I have it on "vibrate."
아니, 삐삐 새로 샀는데
진동으로 해놨거든
See you.
잠깐만
- 안녕
- 어서 와
Hi, you guys!
Look who I found standing
outside the Szechuan Dragon...
드래곤 식당 주차장에
서있는 걸 데려왔어
...staring at a parking meter.
모니카?
- 안녕
-Why aren't you at work?
-Oh, they sent me home.
왜 식당 밖에 있었니?
식당 주인이 가라고 해서
Why?
왜?
Because I don't work
at the Szechuan Dragon.
- 거기가 직장인 줄 알았거든
- 됐어
You really need to get some sleep.
- 너 진짜 수면부족이야
- 나도 알아
I know I do.
- 자기
- 안녕
Guess what? They published my paper.
- 기쁜 소식이야
- 뭔데?
- 내 논문이 출판된대
- 정말?
Really?
Let me see, let me see!
어디 봐, 보자
Rach, look!
레이첼, 이거 봐
안녕!
Where is my strong Ross Skywalker
to come rescue me?
로스님, 어서 와서
저를 구해주세요
There he is!
빨리도 왔네
- 뭐해?
- 행운의
-Wheel!
-Of!
- 바퀴
- 돌려라!
Fortune!
This guy's so stupid.
저 친구 진짜 멍청해
러쉬모어 백작이지!
It's Count Rushmore!
You should really go on this show.
넌 출연하면 잘 할 거야
I got three tickets to
the Rangers tonight. What do you say?
하키 시합 티켓 석 장 구했어
어때, 신나지?
I say I am there!
당연하지, 신난다!
Cool!
Is Ross going too?
- 로스도 가지?
- 아니, 제니스
No. Janice.
제니스?
Janice?
로스 녀석 진짜 불쌍타
늘 우리끼리 갔잖아
Because I just feel bad for Ross,
you know?
우린 끈끈한 삼총사라구!
We always go together. We're like
The Three Hockey-teers, you know?
I may be way out on a limb here,
but do you have a problem with Janice?
내 입장도 생각 해줘
제니스가 그렇게 싫어?
아니
No!
Yes....
응...
표현을 못하겠다
Oh, God, how do I say this?
그리스 식당에 있는
머리 큰 여자 알지?
You know that girl from the
restaurant with the hair?
내가 끔찍해하는 여자?
사람 미치지
That girl that I hate?
She drives me crazy.
Look, I don't hate Janice.
She's just a lot to take, you know?
난 제니스가 싫은 게 아니라
바로 그런 느낌이야
Well, there you go.
그럼 잘됐네
불쌍한 얼굴 하지마
너도 처음엔 싫어했잖아, 맞지?
Don't look at me like that.
She drove you nuts before, remember?
I'm crazy about her now.
This could be the real thing.
지금은 미치게 좋아해
진심으로 좋아한다구
Capital R, capital T!
아주 많이! 더럽게 많이!
Don't worry, those are
the right letters.
내가 너무 오버했냐?
Look, what do you want me to say?
내가 어쩌면 좋겠어?
I want you to say that you like her!
제니스를 좋아해 줘
난 못해, 타고난 웬수인가봐
제니스가 웃기 시작하면
I can't.
It's like a chemical thing.
Every time she starts laughing,
I just wanna...
...pull my arm off so
I have something to throw at her.
내 팔을 뽑아서 그 얼굴에
던지고 싶어지거든
Thanks for trying.
솔직해서 좋다
Oh, and by the way,
there is no Count Rushmore!
아까 답은
러쉬모어 백작이 아냐
Then who's the guy that painted
the faces on the mountain?
백작 아니면 백수냐?
How could you tell her?
어떻게 그런 말을 해?
I didn't think it would be
that big a deal!
별일 아니라고 생각했어
네 친구 피비는 신나게
들었을걸
She didn't think it would be
that big a deal!
Who are you talking to
when you do that?
그럼 넌 누구한테 얘기해?
Look, that was supposed to be
a private, personal thing between us.
그런 건 우리 둘만의
아주 사적인 일이야
피비는 내 친구야
우린 뭐든지 다 얘기해
Phoebe is my girlfriend, okay?
We tell each other everything.
왜 그래?
남자들도 똑같잖아
Guys do the same thing.
I mean, what about all that
locker-room stuff?
남자끼리 모이면
별 얘기 다 한다며?
That's different.
That's like, who dated a stripper?
그건 다른 거야
그건 말이야...
누가 스트립걸을 만났대
희한한 장소를 알고 있대, 등등
Or who did it on the back
of the Staten lsland ferry?
Both of those Joey?
- 그거 조이 얘기지?
- 응
But you don't talk about
your girlfriend...
어쨌든 아무리 친구라 해도
사적인 얘기는 안 해
...and the intimate stuff
you do with her.
Not even with your best friend?
- 친한 친구한테도 안 해?
- 안 해
That is so sad.
참 안됐다
친구가 뭔지 모르고 있어
You're missing out on so much.
I mean, the bonding and the sharing...
우정엔 유대감과 나눔이 있어
친구의 일은 알고 살아야지
...and knowing they're going through
the same thing you are.
그럼, 전부 다 말했어?
So, what, you tell each
other everything?
Pretty much.
거의 다
Did you talk about
the Night of Five Times?
'뜨거운 밤' 얘기도 했어?
Do you tell people about
the Night of Five Times?
'뜨거운 밤' 얘기를 모두가
알고 있냐구?
Honey, that was with Carol.
그건 캐롤과의 일이야
I know, but it's still worth
mentioning, I think.
자기한테 다시
확인시켜 줄려구
Relax every muscle in your body.
몸에 힘을 빼고
편하게 있어
Listen to the plinky-plunky music.
명상 음악에 집중해
Okay, now close your eyes...
이제 눈을 감고
행복했던 장소를 생각해
...and think of a happy place.
Tell me your happy place.
어딘지 말해봐
Richard's living room, drinking wine.
리차드 네 거실,
와인을 마시며...
됐어, 리차드는 안돼
잔을 내려놓고 어서 나와
No, no, no. Not a Richard thing.
Just put down the glass and get out.
I'm sorry, but that's my happy place.
거기가 행복했던 장소야
그럼 내 장소를 이용해보자
아무 것도 만지지마
Okay, fine. Use my happy place.
Just don't move anything in there.
I'll try not to.
그래, 안 만질게
Okay. All right, so,
you're in a meadow...
좋아, 넌 초원에 있어
하늘엔 수많은 별들이...
... millions of stars in the sky
그이와 헤어진 게 실수니?
You think breaking up was a mistake?
행복한 장소에선
질문은 안 받아
There are no questions
in the happy place.
따스한 미풍이 불어오고
나뭇가지 사이로 달빛이 보여...
Just the warm breeze and the
moonlight flowing through the trees.
날 잊었나봐
연락도 없잖아
I'll bet he's over me.
I'll bet he's fine.
그런 상상은 이런 풍경과
안 어울리니까 제발 멈춰 줘
Betting and wagering of any kind
are not permitted in the happy place.
아름다운 폭포에, 샘물이 솟고
시냇물이 졸졸 흐르는...
There's just, you know,
the lovely waterfalls...
...and the trickling fountains...
...and the calming sounds
of the babbling brook.
Okay, this isn't working.
됐어, 소용없어
I'm still awake,
and now I have to pee.
오줌마려서 안되겠어
So I hear...
날 싫어한다고 들었어
...you hate me!
싫단 말은 안 했어
너무 예민한 단어잖아
I never said hate.
I was very careful about that.
네 팔을 뽑아서 나한테
던지고 싶다는 말을 했다며?
A little birdie told me you wanted to
rip your arm off and throw it at me.
And you got "hate" from that?
You're taking a big leap there.
그게 싫다는 뜻은 아니지
너무 앞서가지마
All right, fine, fine, fine!
알았어, 좋아
됐어, 됐어!
We have got to do something about
our little situation here.
이 상황을 해결 해보자
잘 들어봐
So this is my idea.
우리 서로 알 시간을
가져보면 어때?
You and me spending
some quality time together.
그건 좀...
But what does that
챈들러를 위해서야
For Chandler!
Okay. I'm in.
좋아, 하자
Okay! This is what we'll call it:
Joey and Janice's Day of Fun!
이제부터 '조이와 제니스
친구되기'를 하는 거야
A whole day?
하루 종일 해야돼?
Yes, because that's how long
it takes to love me.
응, 날 좋아하려면
그 정도는 걸려
그래, 챈들러가 그러더라
Yeah, I know.
I sleep in the next room.
소포가 와서 봤더니 리차드가
주문했던 비디오였어
So I went down to the post office...
...and it turns out it was
those videos that I ordered...
...for Richard about the Civil War.
남북전쟁에 관한 건데
그이가 좋아했어
He loved the Civil War.
- 집에 데려다 줄까?
- 응
Do you want us to take you home?
Or maybe to a galaxy far, far away.
우리 스타워즈나 다시 볼까?
Women tell each other everything!
Did you know that?
여자들은 뭐든 다 말한대
그거 알고 있냐?
응
No, Chandler, everything.
그게 아냐, 전부 다야
Like stuff you like. Stuff she likes.
침실 얘기까지 다 한대, 시간이
어떻고, 테크닉에 정력, 크기...
Technique. Stamina. Girth.
Girth?
크기?
Why? Why? Why?
왜? 왜? 왜?
왜 그런 얘길 한대?
Why would they do this?
Rachel says sharing's great
and supposedly...
레이첼이 친구랑 뭐든 나눠보래
우리도 해볼까?
...we ought to be doing it.
Do you want to?
넌 어때?
We're not gonna talk about girth,
are we?
- 설마 크기 얘기는 아니지?
- 아냐
- 그럼 좋아
- 할까?
All right, you go first.
그럼, 너 먼저 해
Okay. Okay, I'll go first.
- 좋아, 먼저 하지
- 그래
So the other night...
레이첼과 성적 환상에 대한
얘기를 했는데
...Rachel and I are in bed
talking about fantasies...
...and I happened to describe
a particular...
내가 구체적인 예를 들었어
스타워즈 알지?
... Star Wars thing
Princess Leia and the gold bikini.
- 레아 공주와 금색 비키니?
- 맞아!
나도 알지
I know!
그래... 와우!
말하니까 좋다
Well, that was easy.
이제, 너 해봐
Okay, you go.
- 그래
- 해봐
Okay, you know when you're
in bed with a woman...
너도 알겠지만
여자랑 침대에 있을 때...
응
서로 장난도 치고 그러다가
문득 뭔가가 떠오르지
...fooling around...
...and you get all these
mental images in your brain?
수퍼모델이나...
Like Elle MacPherson
or the girl at the Xerox place?
- 그 복사집 아가씨...
- 배꼽에 링 단 아가씨?
-With the bellybutton ring?
-I know.
- 죽이지
- 그래
And then all of a sudden,
your mom pops into your head.
그런데 갑자기 머리에서
엄마가 튀어나오시지
And you're, like,
"Mom, get out of here!"
"엄마, 어서 사라져줘요"라고
소리쳐보지만, 이미 끝이야
But after that,
you can't think of anything else.
And you can't stop what you're doing.
So it's kind of like you're...
그렇다고 하던 걸
멈출 수도 없고... 그거 알잖아...
...you know...
알지?
...you know....
You don't know!
몰라?
Your mom?
엄마? 지금 엄마라고 했냐?
대체 무슨 소리야?
You're telling me about your mom?
What's the matter with you?
-You said
-I said "share," not "scare"!
- 우리 서로...
- 재수 없게 그딴 소리를 하냐!
저리 꺼져
Go sit over there!
- 우리 왔어
- 친구야
We're back!
What are you guys doing together?
둘이 웬일이야?
'조이와 제니스 친구되기'!
Joey and Janice's Day of Fun!
Really?
정말?
야구보고 중국음식도 먹었어
난 제니스가 정말 좋아
We went to a Mets game.
We got Chinese food.
And, you know, I love this woman.
You have got competition, buddy.
질투 나지? 친구야
Well, I just came by
to give you a kiss.
자기랑 뽀뽀하러 온 거야
I have to go pick up the baby.
So, I'll see you later, sweetheart.
우리 애 데리러 가야돼
나중에 봐, 자기
You too, Chandler.
자기도 안녕!
-You still can't stand her, can you?
-I'm sorry, I tried! I really did!
지금도 제니스 별로지?
안됐지만, 노력은 했어
I appreciate you giving it a shot.
노력해준 건 고마워
But you know, the good thing...
어쨌든 기분 좋은 건
내가 아직도 살아있단 거야
...is that we spent the whole day
together and I survived.
And what's even more amazing,
so did she.
더 놀라운 건
제니스도 살아있단 거지
It was Bat Day at Shea Stadium.
둘 다 경기에만 집중했어
그래, 잘했다
I guess that's something.
Oh, man, that's huge!
그래, 대단했지
Now I know I can stand to be
around her. Which means...
이제 제니스에 대한
면역이 생겼으니까
... I get to hang out with you.
같이 다녀도 괜찮아
그게 중요하지
Which is kind of
the whole point anyway.
좋아
Oh, hey! We stopped by
the coffee shop and ran into Ross.
챈들러, 오는 길에 카페에서
로스를 만났어
Oh, God.
이런...
If it makes you feel any better,
I do it too.
위로가 될지 모르겠지만
나도 똑같아
-Really?
-Oh, yeah!
- 정말이야?
- 그래
I always picture your mom
when I'm having sex.
난 침대에 있을 때
너네 엄마를 생각해
April 12, 1861.
1861년 4월 12일
남부연합의 군대는
섬터 요새를 포격하였다
The United States garrison
at Fort Sumter was fired upon.
It is now under bombardment by
남북전쟁의 포문을 연...
Dad! What are you doing?
아빠, 웬일이세요?
네 엄마도 놀러가고 해서
우리 이쁜 모니카 보러왔지
It's your mother's bridge night, so l
came into the city for a Moni-cuddle.
Since when did you start
smoking cigars?
언제부터 담배 피웠니?
피우는 게 아니라 그냥
냄새만 맡는 거예요
I don't.
I just like the smell of them.
So what are you really doing here?
그런데, 정말 웬일이세요?
I just wanted to make sure
you're okay.
네가 잘 있나 보러 온 거야
Why wouldn't I be okay?
무슨 소리 들으셨어요?
리차드 만났다
I saw Richard.
넌 어떠니?
So how you doing?
I'm fine.
좋아요,
좀 피곤한데 괜찮아요
I'm just a little tired,
but I'm okay.
-How's Richard doing?
-You don't want to know.
- 리차드는 어때요?
- 힘들지 않겠니?
No, I really, really do.
아뇨, 그냥 궁금해서요
Well, he's doing terrible!
꼴이 말이 아니더구나
Really?
정말이요?
바바라와 헤어진 것 보다
더 힘든가봐
Worse than when he broke up
with Barbara.
-You're not just saying that, are you?
-No, the man is a mess!
- 위로하시는 거예요?
- 아니, 정말 끔찍했어
Was he crying?
- 울던가요?
- 아니
Do you think he was waiting till
after you left, so he could cry?
아빠 몰래 뒤에서
울던 눈치였어요?
Maybe.
그런 거 같다
그렇군요
I think so.
Honey, relationships are hard.
Like with your mom and me.
얘야, 남녀관계는 힘든 거다
네 엄마와 나도 그랬어
You know, after we graduated from
college, we broke up for a while.
대학 졸업하고
잠시 헤어졌었어
It seems her father,
your grandfather...
네 외할아버지는 엄마에게
유럽 여행을 가라고 했어
...wanted her to travel around Europe
like he did.
Of course, he got to do it
on Uncle Sam's nickel...
물론, 그 분은 유럽에
계셨을 때 말이지
... because he was also strafing
German troop trains at the time.
독일군하고 전투를 한
추억이 있었는지...
However....
Okay, here we go.
이제 시작한다
자바에게 잡혔어요,
당신이...
I am Jabba's prisoner.
And you...
... have a really weird look
on your face.
표정이 왜 그래?
자기, 뭐야?
What? Honey, what is it?
Did I get the hair wrong?
뭐 이상해? 머리 모양 바꿔?
상상하던 대로가 아니야?
Or what? Did you just
picture it differently? What?
아니, 너 때문이 아냐
그냥...
It's not you.
It's....
왜 그래? 자기야
나도 기분 나빠지려고 해
What is it? Come on, sweetie.
You're, like, freaking me out here.
I hate Chandler.
The bastard ruined my life!
챈들러 녀석이
내 인생을 망쳐놨어